<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="configuring">

	<title>Configuring</title>
	<para>
		Now that you have set up the Gateway you must configure it to suit your requirements. &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; comes with an easy to use CLI (Shell) to allow easy configuration and management. This chapter will help you configure the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;.
	</para>
	<section id="configuring_ss7">
		<title>Configuring the SS7 Stack</title>
		<para>
			You must configure the SS7 stack prior to configuring CAMEL Gateway. For details on configuring the SS7 Stack please refer to the Restcomm SS7 Stack User Guide.
			You must first start the Shell as explained in the previous chapter and connect to the managed instance prior to configuring the Stack. 
			The Restcomm SS7 Stack User Guide lists all available Shell commands to configure SS7. In addition, help files are available all the commands provided.
		</para> 
	</section>

	<section id="setting_camel_routing_rules">
		<title>Configuring CAMEL Gateway</title>
		<para>
			You must configure Routing Rule for the Gateway to forward all incoming CAP operations to third party application over HTTP. 
			You can do this by using the <literal>camel set route</literal> command to forward all request to same URL irrespective of networkId (multi tenancy).</para>
			<para>
			For multi tenancy use command <literal>camel networkrule create</literal> for each networkId. If for any given network, there is no rule defined, &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;
			will use the default defined by <literal>camel set route</literal>
			</para>
		<section id="setting_camel_routing_rules_create">
		<title>Create new Routing Rule</title>
<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>Command:</term>
					<listitem><para>camel set route</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>SYNOPSIS</term>
					<listitem><para>camel set route &lt;url&gt;</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>DESCRIPTION</term>
					<listitem><para>This command is used to create a new routing rule for camel gateway.</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>EXAMPLES</term>
					<listitem><para>
<screen><![CDATA[
camel set route http://localhost:8080/camegatewaydemo/test
]]>
</screen>The above command will create routing rule in the CAMEL Gateway to forward all 
	     incoming CAP operations to third party application (if multi tenancy is not used
	     or for networkId for which no networkrule is created).
				</para>

				</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
		</section>

<section id="setting_camel_routing_rules_show">
		<title>View CAMEL Routing Rules</title>
<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>Command:</term>
					<listitem><para>camel get route</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>SYNOPSIS</term>
					<listitem><para>camel get route</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>DESCRIPTION</term>
					<listitem><para>This command is used to view details of configured routing rules in the
	CAMEL Gateway.</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
					<term>EXAMPLES</term>
					<listitem><para>
<screen><![CDATA[
camel get route 

route = http://localhost:8080/camegatewaydemo/test

]]>
</screen>

				</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="setting_camel_routing_rules_create_mt">
		<title>Create new Routing Rule for multi tenancy</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel networkrule create

SYNOPSIS
	camel networkrule create <network-id> <url>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to create a new routing rule for a network id.

EXAMPLES
	camel networkrule create 0 http://10.199.7.23:8080/camel
	
	The above command will create a new network rule in the CAMEL Gateway for
	the network id 0. When the CAMEL Gw detects incoming CAP message from
	network id 0, gateway will direct the HTTP POST request to the URL 
	http://10.199.7.23:8080/camel as specified by the routing rule.

SEE ALSO
	camel networkrule, camel networkrule delete, camel networkrule show
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="setting_camel_routing_rules_delete_mt">
		<title>Delete Routing Rule for multi tenancy</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel networkrule delete

SYNOPSIS
	camel networkrule delete <network-id>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to delete an existing routing rule for a network id.

EXAMPLES
	camel networkrule delete 0
	
	The above command will delete the network routing rule in the CAMEL Gateway
	for the network id 0

SEE ALSO
	camel networkrule, camel networkrule create, camel networkrule show
			]]></screen>
		</section>	
		<section id="setting_camel_routing_rules_show_mt">
		<title>Show Routing Rule for multi tenancy</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel networkrule show

SYNOPSIS
	camel networkrule show

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all configured network routing
	rules in the CAMEL Gateway.

SEE ALSO
	camel networkrule, camel networkrule create, camel networkrule delete
			]]></screen>
		</section>	
		
		<section id="setting_camel_noactivitytimeout">
		<title>Set No Activity Timeout for Dialog</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel set noactivitytimeout

SYNOPSIS
	camel set noactivitytimeout <timeout-sec>

DESCRIPTION
	Once TCAP dialog is established, if there is no activity for 'x' 
	seconds, it will timeout. 'x' is configurable, please see 
	tcap set dialogidletimeout command. However in case of Camel 
	Applications, the dialog can live much longer (for example call).
	Camel gateway will keep renewing the TCAP dialog automatically, 
	however if peer side is faulty or application didn't send proper 
	response to end TCAP dialog, there will be leak and dialog will 
	remain alive forever. To avoid such situations set the 
	noactivitytimeout in seconds such that if there is no activity 
	in dialog for 'noactivitytimeout' sec, Camel gateway will call 
	application indicating same. Application may take corrective action 
	like End TCAP dialog or send empty response back in which case TCAP 
	dialog continues and Camel gateway again makes call to application 
	after 'noactivitytimeout'

PARAMETERS
	Standard Parameters

	timeout-sec		-	timeout in seconds after which application must 
						be called if there is no activity in TCAP dialog.
						Default value is 3600 seconds (1 hour).

SEE ALSO
	camel get noactivitytimeout
			]]></screen>
		</section>			
		
		<section id="getting_camel_noactivitytimeout">
		<title>Get No Activity Timeout for Dialog</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel get noactivitytimeout

SYNOPSIS
	camel set noactivitytimeout

DESCRIPTION
	Retruns the noactivitytimeout value.
	
	Once TCAP dialog is established, if there is no activity for 'x' 
	seconds, it will timeout. 'x' is configurable, please see 
	tcap set dialogidletimeout command. However in case of Camel 
	Applications, the dialog can live much longer (for example call).
	Camel gateway will keep renewing the TCAP dialog automatically, 
	however if peer side is faulty or application didn't send proper 
	response to end TCAP dialog, there will be leak and dialog will 
	remain alive forever. To avoid such situations set the 
	noactivitytimeout in seconds such that if there is no activity 
	in dialog for 'noactivitytimeout' sec, Camel gateway will call 
	application indicating same. Application may take corrective action 
	like End TCAP dialog or send empty response back in which case TCAP 
	dialog continues and Camel gateway again makes call to application 
	after 'noactivitytimeout'

PARAMETERS
	
SEE ALSO
	camel set noactivitytimeout
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		
		<section id="setting_camel_updateassignedinvokeids">
		<title>Set Update Assigned Invoke Ids</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel set updateassignedinvokeids

SYNOPSIS
	camel set updateassignedinvokeids <true | false>

DESCRIPTION
	Once Application sends back HTTP response carrying CAP messages as XML 
	payload to be sent to peer, Camel gateway will send these invokes to 
	peer and assign InvokeId generated by Camel gateway. HTTP Application 
	wouldn't be aware of which invoke id belongs to which CAP message and 
	hence if there are some error's reported by peer (carrying invoke id), 
	HTTP application wouldn't know this error is for which invoke? To avoid 
	such situation set the updateAssignedInvokeIds to true so Camel gateway 
	will send back HTTP request carrying all the assigned invokeId's as soon as it sends Invoke to peer

PARAMETERS
	Standard Parameters

	true | false		-	If set to true, camel gateway will send the HTTP
						request carrying assigned id's as explained above

SEE ALSO
	camel get updateassignedinvokeids
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		
		<section id="getting_camel_updateassignedinvokeids">
		<title>Get Update Assigned Invoke Ids</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	camel get updateassignedinvokeids

SYNOPSIS
	camel get updateassignedinvokeids

DESCRIPTION
	
	Retruns the value of updateassignedinvokeids
	
PARAMETERS
	Standard Parameters

	

SEE ALSO
	camel set updateassignedinvokeids
			]]></screen>
		</section>														
		
	</section>
</chapter>
