<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter
	id="pre-requisites">
	<title>Pre-Requisites</title>
 <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;'s core requirement is Java. The following table details the Hardware, Operating System and Software requirements for new installation of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;. 
<table
						frame="all"
						pgwide="1">
						<title>Installation Pre-Requisites</title>
						<tgroup cols='3' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
							<colspec
								colnum="1"
								colname="c0" />
							<colspec
								colnum="2"
								colname="c1" />
							<colspec
								colnum="3"
								colname="c2" />
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Component</entry>
									<entry>Requirement</entry>
									<entry>Notes</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>System Requirements</entry>
									<entry>Intel Pentium 1 GHz or faster for simple applications. Hard disk space of at least 20MB. RAM of at least 1.5 GB</entry>	
									<entry>The higher the amount of RAM and processing power, the better the throughput that can be achieved</entry>	
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>TDM Hardware</entry>
									<entry>For legacy SS7 links, you must have <literal>dahdi</literal> or <literal>dialogic</literal> cards installed along with their native libraries.</entry>	
									<entry> </entry>	
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Operating System</entry>
									<entry>The platform can be installed on any OS that supports Java and SCTP. But native libraries for SS7 cards are compiled only for Linux at the moment and therefore supported only on Linux Operating System.</entry>
									<entry>The libraries will be compiled for Windows in future releases.</entry>	
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Java</entry>
									<entry>You must have a working Java Run-time Environment (JRE) or Java Development Kit (JDK) installed on your system. The only supported version is JAVA 7. Oracle JDK is recommended. </entry>
									<entry> </entry>	
									
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>SCTP libraries</entry>
									<entry>If you intend to use <literal>SIGTRAN (M3UA)</literal>, you must have the <literal>lksctp</literal> library installed. The Linux Kernel Stream Control Transmission Protocol (<literal>lksctp</literal>) library provides SCTP implementation.</entry>
									<entry>For more details on downloading and installing <literal>lksctp</literal>, please refer to <ulink url="http://lksctp.sourceforge.net/"></ulink></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
</para>
<important>					<para>
			
 You must ensure that the <literal>JAVA_HOME</literal> Environment variable is correctly set for the user account(s) that will run the server. For more details on setting this variable, please refer to the <xref linkend="jboss_home_setup" />.
					</para>
</important>
</chapter>

